Okay, that's good.
Hold.
I'm just, I was just getting myself organized.
Alright, so we're okay.
Let me see.
you showed up in Phandalin, you showed up in, uh, Neverwinter.
Yes.
And, uh, you had a business deal with Gundrun.
MMHM.
Um, actually, uh, sorry, I should have made this.
I think I misinformed you.
Gundrun and his warrior escort, uh, Gundrun and his escort, Sildar Hallwinter.
Uh, rode ahead of you.
So while you guys were taking this slow wagon, they, they had ridden ahead of you.
Uh, New York.
Oh, okay, okay.
Earlier, I remember Gundrun was telling he was gonna come after like two or three days.
It hadn't.
Yes, yes, and I was very confused with that, and um.
I was supposed to go.
Okay.
So, let's just say I'm a little bit, uh, a little bit of a retcon, a little bit of a retcon.
Amham.
Uh, my, my mistake.
Yeah, so Gundrun and his, uh, his escort Sildar Hallwinter, have already, now, that explains why.
I was very confused with that, okay.
This is what happens when I have dyslexia, I get confused.
Okay.
I get confused.
Alright, so good.
I was like, that's not how I remember the adventure.
What am I doing wrong?
Is it sits?
I read it five times incorrectly.
Alright, so you began, you began, you made your deal, uh, Gundrun and Sildar have decided, are, have headed out before you, that's why they said meet us.
At the, uh, at Barthen's Provisions, and, like, worry if I don't come back after a day or.
And, uh, you met Pip, um, and he said he's going to, uh, Phandalin because small towns need strong backs and sharper eyes.
Sister Garaele is traveling to Phandalin after receiving a troubling letter from an old dwarven contact who works claims near Triboar.
And Vera of the Blue Candle is following the trail of her missing mentor, who vanished while investigating fragments of some stone.
His last known destination?
Amham.
Was Phandalin.
Yes.
She has a charcoal map covered in nebulous annotations, a blue candle wrapped in cloth, and a half-burned note that reads.
Was in Phandalin.
Yes.
The town is not a prize.
It is the threshold.
Mokay.
And, um, when you looked at the map, it looks like the map of somebody who's suffering from one too many paranoid, delusional conspiracies.
Amham.
We've established that you're a rogue, right?
Yes.
Right, we've established that you're a rogue, and your backstory is that you were, uh, you were part of the criminal element of Neverwinter, and uh.
The jobs in Neverwinter got a little bit too hot, and somebody said you could make some easy money by just taking some provisions down.
Uh yes.
Yes.
And, um.
And so, as a result of that, you're kind of, like, going.
Uh, I'm, uh, I'm good.
Um, you, you, you got the, you showed up at this tavern, you got the job, and now you signed a contract.
A very nice contract, if I might say so myself.
Amham.
Uh, you were able to get 19 gold pieces, um, and then as you got into the wagon, you realized that.
Um, okay.
Uh, what's his name?
Gundrun was not going to lose any money on this, and you're beginning to realize that Vera.
And Pip and Sister Garaele wanted to go to Phandalin and paid for the privilege of coming along with you.
Yes.
Um, and so, uh, you're, you're about a few miles, uh, right of the Triboar Trail.
Amham.
Uh, so I'm a few miles ahead of the Triboar Trail.
And, uh, the wagon strikes a black stone half-buried in the road.
It cracks under the wheel with a sound like breaking glass.
Hmm, okay.
I wonder what that is.
That doesn't sound like a stone.
Um.
Let me get down and check what happened to the wagon.
Alright, um.
So I'm gonna stop the wagon.
Yeah, okay.
Okay, stop the wagon.
Alright, the wagon stopped.
Um, Zevran, what is your perception?
Wait, oh, it's my perception.
It's two plus.
Forgot where do I roll?
It's in the roll 20, right?
Yeah, you don't look, so look at your passive perception.
Go to your paw, go to your, uh, web browser.
Yes.
Character sheet, yes.
Alright, you see, um, top left hand?
Okay, here, hold on.
I'll just show you now, and so.
Oh, the passive perception is 2012-12 backslash.
Right, right, alright, so, um, let me.
Alright.
I have to look at the character sheets of these sidekicks.
I'm sharing my screen so you can just see that.
Yeah, yeah, no, no, no, no, that's a very good best practice.
Okay, okay, thank you.
Alrighty.
Um.
You notice that, um.
Vera's wrapped blue candle gives a one-off pulse.
So as your, as your, as you get down.
You get off the, uh, the wagon, right?
And umha.
Just for a moment, you see the shadow of a tall, broken obelisk.
Scratching across the road, though nothing is there.
Okay.
Do you say anything to your colleagues, or do you just so I see a shadow of the obelisk?
Yes, of a tall, broken obelisk stretching across the road, though nothing is there.
I'm gonna ask one of them if, uh.
ask them if one of their items fell down, like, hey guys, is this one of your.
Does this belong to one of you?
Okay, so you go to the, so, okay, so, no, sorry, sorry, let me try this, so let me make sure you understood what happened.
You're on the, you're on the wagon.
All of a sudden, you go.
You go over something which over a black over something that caused the cracks.
There you go.
When that happens, you see, just for a second, the shadow of a tall, broken obelisk stretching across the road, though nothing is there.
Okay.
Oh, do you guys see this?
So, I'm gonna ask to all of them, like, did you guys see the same thing?
Um.
Roll your insight.
Or investigation.
How do I do that?
Good luck.
I don't know, investigation is, um.
Oh, I forgot.
Where do I go?
It's not good.
Go back, go back, go back, go back to that.
Yes, click on this.
Do this on that.
Oh, okay.
Okay.
Similar then?
No, it's a 15, see?
11 plus 4 backslash.
Okay, 15, yes.
Right, right.
Now, oh, I realized something.
Can you go install a Chrome plugin?
Called Beyond 20 Backslash.
Okay, that's interesting.
It basically will cause the die rolls to appear in roll 20 backslash.
It's uh, yes.
Alright, so they're done.
So now go to your, whenever you roll the dice, go, like, roll a die.
Thank you.
No, go to D backslash and D beyond.
Go into D backslash and D beyond.
It says there, okay, this is a new, go to features and traits.
Go over here.
Click on that.
Alright, so what happens is that it, the way it works is it goes, when you click on that, it reads all of this and updates its state of your character.
Now go click on this to roll the dice.
Click on word, this one.
Does it, whatever, click on the die, yeah, click on that, doesn't.
So what'll happen is now if you go to roll 20 backslash.
Okay.
Yeah, that sounds good.
That way, that way, um.
We have a log of the pedestrians.
Yeah, I mean, that way we don't have to go between two things to figure out what the die roll is, and blah blah blah.
It also rolls all of your, it does all of the, uh, bonuses correctly, so you don't have to go figure that out.
Does that make sense?
So I click on this, the, this one?
No.
Now go to your go to your character sheet.
Go to my character.
Character and just press on this one.
That's supposed to make sure.
That would be a natural 20 backslash.
Okay, I understand.
Got it?
Got it.
Alrighty.
Okay, so back to, alright.
So.
The rogue sees, for just a moment, the shadow of a, you see, just for a moment, Zevran sees, just for a moment, the shadow of a tall, broken.
Nothing was there, it's just like a shadow with nothing casting the shadow.
Amham.
Um, you turn and you roll the twelve, and so you notice, that Vera's, just out of the corner of your eye, you notice that Vera's wrapped blue candle gives off one pulse of life.
Hm, okay.
Uh, and it, it, it did obviously the same.
Um there's a ring.
What?
The flame goes away?
Yeah, yeah.
It gives off, like, it doesn't turn on, it, like, gives off a pulse of light.
Thank you.
And it's one of, uh, the Sister Garaele's candle.
Um.
Oh, no, no, that's, uh, Vera's.
The, she's the, um, the, the.
You got it.
Amham.
You're on the map on your screen.
That's your screen, not my screen.
A Vera is the tiefling.
Um, who's thinking that her, her, um?
Her mentor has disappeared.
So Vera, just make sure that you can see there.
So yeah, Vera of the blue candle, her blue candle lit up.
Okay, yeah, I see a candle.
So it's not her candle.
There's a flicker of light, basically.
Yeah, so her candle sort of, like, it doesn't light up as a candle, it, like.
It's in the corner of my blinks.
So, um, see you.
Yeah, I'm gonna ask her, like, why is that blinking?
And uh, maybe I can do an investigation.
Roll an investigation.
And what did you see?
56 backslash.
So that's six.
Um, yeah, you got nothing.
Okay.
You got nothing.
Thank you.
Um, do you want to call attention to it, or do you want to just, like, you know, let it be?
Yeah, I can do the presentation, but I want to call attention.
You want me to try that?
Okay, give me one second.
I need to go check something.
I'll be.
Okay.
Alright.
Um What does she say?
Um she looks at it and says, I don't know.
But I know, I know, but then she says, you know, the usual thing people say in these I did not roll the persuasion yet.
Oh, you didn't roll the persuasion?
Sorry.
She keeps it's a ten backslash.
She, um, she does, what does she do?
Let's decide what she does.
You rolled a ten, is that what you rolled?
Yes.
Alright, um.
She looks at you and says, well.
It's a.
I don't know.
I don't know what this is.
I just know that it somehow is connected to my mentor disappearing.
Who's your mentor?
Um.
Who was my mentor?
Oh, um.
So what did you ask her?
Okay, I actually found this.
Mentor's name, and I was.
The next thing I was gonna ask is about the story of that mentor's disappearance.
Oh, okay, so, oh, okay, so she, she, she, she observes that she doesn't know exactly what this light gives, but she does, she does know that it, she basically goes, I don't know what this is.
I do know that he was looking for it.
Uh, he was, he was looking for, it was something that was conductive, related to his research.
Amham.
Um, she pauses for a minute and says.
He was investigating fragments of an ancient obelisk.
Yeah, that makes sense.
His last known desti, his last known destination, was Phandalin.
Thank you.
Which is why I'm going there.
That makes sense.
Right.
So, no wonder we found an obelisk on the road.
You didn't find an obelisk.
You saw a shadow of an obel.
Wait a minute.
No, the something cracked on the wheel.
So, you guys, we haven't gone to see what cracked under the wheel.
All you have seen.
Oh, I see it's the shadow of anomalies.
Okay, okay, so I'm gonna go check.
Like, all of it, so imagine that the road's clear, and all of a sudden, just for a minute, the minute you run over something that cracks.
You see a shadow of an obelisk.
No obelisk, no obelisk.
Hmm, okay.
K, no obelisk.
Um, so I'm gonna go to the wheel and uh check what cracked under it.
Um, no, uh.
It's a blackstone.
It's just a stone.
Okay.
Uh, I'll just pick it up no matter what.
Alright, you pick it up and put it in your belongings.
Yes, I just put it in the pocket.
Do I have to roll anything?
No, I don't see it.
No, no, you just put it in your pocket.
Just put it in the notes of things that you have.
Okay, just typed it in the chat.
You got it.
What?
I typed in the chat.
Uh, wait a second, was I maintaining the notes?
Yeah, so did you, you put the notes, and it says, now Zevran put the blackstone in his pocket?
Yeah.
Yeah, that's the note.
Cool.
Alright, so yes, you have the blackstone in the pocket.
Alright.
Yes, yes.
Alrighty.
Ah, you're showing me the, um.
So, alright, so let's see what happens.
You turn on the Triboar Trail.
Turn around there.
You've been on the Triboar Trail for about half a day and are nearing a side road heading south to Phandalin.
As you come around a bend, you stumble upon the scene of a recent battle.
The woods press close to the trail here, with a steep embankment and dense thickets on either side.
Two horses wander the road, sniffing at ransacked personal effects.
Here, so let me just.
That is correct.
You should be seeing nothing.
But, uh, you should.
We'll be seeing something now, except the dynamic lighting wasn't set.
No, I'm not seeing anything.
Yeah, I know, I know, I know.
Okay.
I am aware of this.
It's all black.
Okay.
It was, oh.
So I need to, it's got dynamic lighting, but it's not set.
By default.
And do that setting.
Because I forgot what I needed to do.
Two houses.
Alrighty.
The wood press close to the trail here.
As you come around the bend, you stumble upon the scene of a recent battle.
The woods press close to the trail here.
With a steep embankment and dense thickets on either side, two horses.
Wander the roads, sniffing at ransacked personal effects.
Personal what?
A personal effect.
Things that belong to people.
Okay.
Personal possessions.
Alright, so, um, do you want to get off and check it out?
Like, what's your plan?
Uh, it could be an ambulance.
So, uh, first, I'm gonna try to get past the horses and then stop the carriage.
And look into the woods or scan the woods.
So you're gonna try to get.
Alright, so your plan is to, like, go over here?
Yep.
And my plan is to go on to the other side of the houses.
Okay.
And then scan the rooms for any therapy.
So, maybe investigation.
Alright, so as you get over here, as you get like over here.
Um.
Four goblins erupted.
Get out of the darkness.
Sorry.
Out of the forest.
Okay.
And so let me just.
Make sure to show up over here.
And over here.
Okay.
So, uh, roll-y, roll, now we do roll for initiative.
3-2-1.
For initiative.
Nah, how does combat work?
Great question, I'm glad you asked.
So,
The way.
Thank you, thank you.
I don't know.
So.
No, no, I know I realized that I just like I'm I just realized forgot you don't know okay so the way combat works.
Wait actually okay sorry.
Yeah go ahead go ahead.
So click on your character.
Yes.
And now click on, there's a button in your character sheet.
Called initiative, where it says plus five, so yes uh click it.
Now go back to your character sheet, go back to the roll 20 backslash.
Alrighty.
That did not work because you hadn't clicked your character.
Click your character again.
Well, I'll teach you how this works.
Click.
No, no, you have to click him, so that he's clicked.
Can you interact with your character?
On the roadway?
Could you move him?
Could you try moving him?
Ah, backslash.
This is not the right one.
Zevran.
Ah, murder.
What's happening?
Could you try moving the character sheet?
Could you try moving your character?
Yeah, I can move the entire map if not the factory.
You can't move the character?
Not already, please.
You can't click them.
Alright, alright, no, no, it's, it's, uh, it's, you know.
Right.
Could you try moving him now?
Can you click on him?
Still can't click on him.
No, no, no.
Oh, you're on the map tool.
Use the pointer tool.
Still can't click on him.
Oh, that was the problem.
I gave you.
Oh, yeah, I can.
I can move it now.
Could you move him now?
Excellent backslash.
Yes.
Awesome.
Alright, so hold on.
Go put him back where he was.
Now, click on him.
And now go, you've got him clicked.
Now go to your initiative die, and go back to the D backslash indeed beyond character sheet.
No.
Enroll for initiative?
Okay.
24 backslash.
And you'll see that if you go back to the roll 20 backslash, you will see that it now says 24 backslash.
That's your initiative.
Amhom.
Okay.
For sidekicks, I will not roll for initiative, I will just use their, uh.
I'll just use their default.
Ah, so what is his default?
His is 11 backslash.
So what does a negotiated mean?
Ah, give me one second.
So initiative is the order in which combat occurs.
I see, okay.
About the characters, right?
Not the goblins or the other.
No, no, everybody gets an initiative role, it's just, I have to.
Amhom.
We just roll for their initiative.
Oh, even the goblins get an option to also.
Yes, yes.
Alright, so.
So I rolled our initiative.
Over here.
Alright.
Okay, so they appear out of the, so now, so now this is the order in which actions occur.
Amhom.
So, uh.
Oh, so I have to start first.
So the goblins, are they?
Can I see them?
Uh, yes, you can see them.
They're basically it, yes, if you can, in general, if you can see them on the thing, you can see them, so, like.
Does that make sense?
Amham, okay, okay, yeah.
Um.
Just to, uh, let's, we need a C.
Let's say you've got a cart here.
Amhom.
Alright, so there's a cart over there.
Alright.
So what would you like to do?
That's the card I've been driving, right?
Yes.
Okay, what would I like to do?
Um, I don't have any weapons, I suppose.
No, you do have weapons.
You have bows, you have, like, swords, you have many weapons.
Oh, yeah, I have crossbow, hand, righteous, scimitar, flashbolt, single weapons, but it's an ambush.
Okay, yes.
Which is?
Yeah, yeah, I got that.
So, I'll use a crossbow and uh aim at uh, where's the request?
Alright, let's give them numbers.
Let's give them numbers so you can, like, know who they are.
Okay, okay.
Can you see those numbers?
You're not colorblind.
I played D backslash and D with someone who was colorblind, and they didn't tell me, and they couldn't see the colors until I got it.
So the reason I'm asking is, please tell me so I use the right colors.
I can.
Yes, I can see that.
Okay.
Yeah.
Yeah, yeah.
You used a blue color for one of those.
That was, that was because I was, like, fits it put.
On on purpose?
No, no, it was an accident.
It was A.
Excellent, okay.
Okay.
I'm gonna aim my crossbow and attack number 3.
Alright, so what you do is you go back to your character sheet.
MMHM.
And you roll, you go to your actions.
You mentioned sections, sections, various sections.
Yes.
Okay.
Sorry.
Alright, and then you click on you click on this here.
Don't know.
Short go.
Yeah, short, actually.
Yeah, short boot, sorry, yeah, yeah.
But on that, yeah, yeah.
Right, but you see where it says an arrow?
Click on.
Okay, being aware of this.
That is, you hit 12, and let's see, let's see if you actually hit.
Alright, so 12?
Let's go back.
So you rolled a 12.
Mhm.
Alright, against who?
Number 3.
Ooh, number 3's, number 3's got a pretty good armor class.
No, you missed.
Wait, what?
Because his armor class is 15.
And you rolled a 12.
How would I know that?
You wouldn't, I would tell you that.
So.
So I rolled.
I chose number 3 based on the initiative numbers.
I thought, you know, he's the least, so I attacked him.
It doesn't matter, they all have the same, okay, so.
Bye.
Mechanically speaking, all monsters have the same armor class, of the same type.
Okay.
To make the GM's lives easy, all goblins have an armor class of 15.
Unless the GM tells you they're wearing fancier armor than usual.
Okay.
Right, does that make sense?
Yes.
So, so, just so we're on, so that, yeah, so, so all.
Goblins are, you know.
Okay, so who's this?
Sorry.
Goblin number four.
Number three.
No, no, you attacked goblin number three and missed.
Goblin number four.
Um, so, you can now move.
Do you want to stand there?
Do you want to go someplace?
Like.
I wanna go behind the cart.
Did you want to go behind the cart, or under the cart, or, like, in the cart?
Like, do you, like, you could try to get some?
Like, kind of try to get some cover yourself from in the cart.
Yeah, instead, I don't think I can cover myself.
The armor is.
Sorry, the arrows are gonna pierce from left and right, so I'm gonna stand behind.
Oh, hold on, hold on.
So, so just, just to be clear, if you go to the cart, you can get partial cover.
I'm gonna stand here because, you know, there are goblins on both sides of the car.
That's my reasoning.
Alright, that's fine.
Okay.
Alright, okay, so you're standing on that side.
Are you standing on one of the twos?
On the back, yeah.
Word.
That's fine, that's fine.
Here.
Yeah, yeah.
So that I'm hidden.
I guess, yeah.
Alright, so Vera.
Okay, this goblin here.
What does he do?
Ours is shortbow.
And at.
Alright.
Sorry.
I need to find his armor class.
Class is 16.
So that is also a miss.
Okay.
Right?
Rather, the goblin missed, right?
Mhm.
And then this goblin.
attacks Sister Mela.
And also misses.
Alright.
Vera of the blue candle goes, this is insanity.
She's, like, terrified.
Yeah.
She's like.
I'm too young backslash.
Um, and so, um, what does she do?
Alright, she casts a firebolt.
5 plus 5 to hit, alright?
So she casts a firebolt.
And misses as well.
Goblin 1.
Goblin, sorry, goblin.
Number 2.
Uh, goblin 2, yep, ye.
Attacks, uh, decides to attack, uh, sister, attacks Sister Mela.
Ooh, and hits for 5 points of damage.
So that does 5 points of damage to Vera.
Um, what's your situation there?
Cause, uh, you can.
So she's down to 3.
Uh, Sister Mela.
And.
I'm shaking it back.
Yeah, no, she's gonna, first, her Sister Mela is going to.
What is she gonna do?
Okay, what you gonna do?
Alright, so she's going to heal.
Because, um.
4-5 points.
So Vera is back to 8 points.
And she will tell Vera to get under the wagon, so Vera hides under the wagon.
Alright.
Pip.
Goes.
I was made for this and charges up with the goblin.
Oh wow, okay.
And he attacks.
MMHM.
Okay, that's what I'm, I keep, I keep getting confused because it, it like suddenly got into a different F okay, so.
Plus 4.
And he misses.
Okay.
A goblin.
This goblin, uh.
Number 3 backslash.
Seeing that Sister Mela is open.
Attacks and actually, I think she hits hits her.
16, and she takes.
Alright.
Okay, so that brings us back to Xenophon.
Now, Xenophon, um, when you attack a gob, when you attack a creature that's within 5 feet of an alley, you get additional damage, so attacking number 2 would probably be the right play.
Okay.
A wait, sorry.
You have what's known as a sneak attack bonus.
Okay.
Bye.
I don't have a snippet of bonus.
Yes, you do.
If you look, bring your, let me show you.
Oh, yeah, you don't need advantage on that, I think, but at least one of your allies is within five minutes.
So when you roll an attack, it will automatically show you the damage with sneak attack.
Thank you.
So, shortbow.
You can either charge up to it.
You can either go and attack.
With, uh, a short sword, or a dagger.
That's fine.
Am I in the five minutes?
No, you have to move.
What's this?
We have to move.
Okay, okay, I can move.
Um, but uh, so I'm gonna move closer to that goblin.
Alright.
No, it's just the same thing.
This is five feet.
Okay, yeah, okay, I'll stay here.
Yeah, so it's in, it's in the, it's in the adjacent square.
Okay.
K yeah, got it.
So, I'm gonna use my shortsword.
Okay, you are not doing very well with your die rolls.
Slide.
Uh, the goblin, uh, misses sister.
misses.
Vera.
Alright, the next goblin.
What does he?
He attacks Thistle and misses, oop, wrong dice.
Or moves in to attack Thistlepip with his scimitar.
And this is spectacularly.
Alright.
Vera pops out.
Vera pops out of her, uh.
Yes.
Uh, from underneath the, um.
The cover?
And what does she do?
And she attacks.
She will use a magic missile.
Doesn't miss, because at this point in time.
Killing these guys seems to be the priority.
Not getting killed, also the priority.
So, magic missile does d4.
Plus 1.
So, she kills one of them.
Right.
What?
Yeah, yeah, I saw that number 2 backslash.
Right, she kills number 2.
So, right.
And then she hides again underneath the wagon.
Okay.
Alright.
Sister Mela.
Decide.
Yes, I will be okay.
Oh, actually, she hides over there.
Sister Mela.
You can target one.
Yeah, but yeah, when she targets one, then she's, like, going, do we want to target one, or do we want to target number three?
One because it was like five feet next to me.
No, no, no, you made the case.
She's going for number one.
Yes.
Alright, so she's gonna use, um.
She's going to use her hammer.
She's going to actually attempt, she's gonna use sacred flame.
She invokes the name of her deity, and, um, hopes that it will cause damage.
And so, the damage is mhm.
Yes, has gotta kill him, the one.
Sacred flame so powerful.
Yeah, I know I just I need to.
I need to find what the saving throw is.
Give me a second, uh, Sister Mela.
Let me see.
Alright, DC12 dexterity.
Alright, makes it saving throw.
Alright, Pip.
Attacks this goblin over here.
Wait, what happened to Mela's attack?
Was it successful?
She missed.
No, it was a miss.
Oh.
Uh, Pip also missed.
Everybody's not having a good day.
Alright.
The goblin.
That's near.
No, no, it's the goblin the goblin.
Oh yeah.
Uh, Sister Mela actually also decides to hide in the, um, under the, uh, the wagon, or rather to get onto that side of the wagon.
MMHM.
The goblin decides that he has to come down, and so he rushes down and attacks her with his scimitar.
No, no.
And hits, and she's down to one hit point.
Alright, Xenophon, you're up.
The obvious thing to do is to attack this guy over here.
This guy, right?
Yeah, I'm gonna move here.
Let me, um, that would work.
You're welcome.
Yeah, you're welcome.
That's why, you know.
It's like, what is this?
Just the piercing damage, right?
Yes.
And what does 1d4 plus 3 mean?
Like, 1d6 plus 3?
That's how much damage you would do.
The dice roll plus 3.
Yes.
But you're within 5 feet, so you need to use your melee weapon, so either the dagger or the shortsword.
Okay, I'm gonna try this one.
Uh, dagger does 1d4, and shortsword does 1d6.
Ah, and also.
Missed last time.
Wait, what is it, d4 and d6?
Yeah, but all that, all that, I, I just, yeah, I just, I forgot to mention something because you have a, d4.
And a DC, because you have A.
Because you have a dagger and a shortsword, you can attack with two weapons at once.
So.
Mhm.
You first attack with a short sword, and then with a dagger.
You have what's known as two weapon ability?
Check.
If you look over here.
Ah.
Oh, yeah, yeah, yeah, two-weapon fighting, yes.
Right, so you can attack once with your dagger, and once with your short sword.
Perfect.
Okay.
First with dagger, I'll try.
Um, I would, I would, uh, okay.
That is, I think, a miss.
That's a miss again.
Roll again.
Yes.
Roll the same thing.
Yep, the short sword now.
Now the short sword.
Sure, sure, okay.
Alright, you finally hit.
And you killed him.
To hit?
He's dead.
Alright, and the reason he's dead is because he did 4 points of damage, plus 5 points of sneak attack damage, for a total of 9 points of damage, and he only had 7 hit points.
So where can I see his points?
And ah, okay, so his points, right, right, right.
I cannot.
Uh, no, no, I, uh, so, I can show you, you can, like.
Do you see a bar now?
Yes.
You can see the bar.
Oh, you put that on top of some, okay.
And so that kind of gives you an indication.
And if you want how many hit points, just ask me, how many hit points does he have left?
I don't keep.
Okay, okay, okay, good.
Yeah.
But, like, if you, the bar tells you generally how many hit points they have, and no.
And so you can make a decision.
Alright.
The goblin.
There's this goblin.
So we both move forward.
Should we, should I move, or was that?
Yeah, yeah, so you should, yeah, Pip.
I mean, Pip already did his act, Pip already did his action, so he's staying there, but you can move if you want.
Yeah, I'm gonna come to the back side of the thank you.
Okay, you're gonna go over there.
Yeah.
Alright.
Alright, so he's gonna attack Pip, because Pip's the only guy that's not, doesn't have any cover.
And misses.
Okay.
Vera.
Casts a magic missile on this guy over here.
And he dies.
Oh no, we don't know.
No, no, it is possible if I could do six points.
Ah, yep, he only he's down to one hit point.
Okay, no, the.
Oh shoot.
Okay.
Alright, Sister Mela casts healing on herself, because, uh, she only has one hit point.
Now she has five hit points.
Six hit points.
No, five.
That's not very good.
Alright, Pip.
Goes.
Ah, decides that he's gonna try to be heroic.
Hits.
Mhm.
Kills.
Ah, no.
Depends on how much damage he does.
Okay.
He does d8 plus 2.
5 points of damage, and I think this guy had 1 hit point, right?
So he's dead.
Yes, he's, in fact, because he only had 1 hit point, he's dead.
Alright, Xenophon, you're.
Okay.
Oh, um.
I'm gonna.
Yeah, I'm gonna move on to this side.
Getting closer.
And then use my shortbow.
Ah, your shortbow has a range of 60 feet, so you're still within, you don't have to move if you don't want to.
Oh, I see, okay, okay.
Then I'm gonna hide behind the wagon and then use my shortbow.
Alright, so.
And roller.
What you do is you use your shortbow and then hide, or, right.
Yeah, yeah.
Alright, go.
Roll.
Okay, so that's, uh.
8 points of piercing damage, but you don't get any sneak attack, you had 1 hit point.
So he's dead.
Hey, okay, that's cool.
Hey.
Yay, you managed to survive your first day.
I had two kills.
Yeah, yeah, hold on, let me.
Tokens.
Nice.
Let me see if I can get this to work.
Give me just one second.
Sometimes I can get it to work, sometimes.
Right, um.
So let me see.
Let me see if this works.
Let me just see if I can get this to work.
I know it's, it's kind of for days, right?
Just give me a second.
Okay.
Surprise.
Can you stop sharing?
Okay.
Did you hear that?
Yeah.
Okay.
The victory sound.
Yes, victory soundtrack.
Alright, so, the first thing you do is you go see what the horses, I presume, are looking, we're looking at.
The horses, in the meantime, have completely freaked out.
Out and ran away, so they're no longer there.
Hey, yes.
But the things, but there was a bunch of personal effects.
Let me just make that here.
Personal effects are over here.
Yep.
So, do you want to go look at them?
Yes.
Wait, you mean artifacts?
But, uh, effects.
You should see it on the map.
Yep.
Effects?
Yes, yes.
Yeah, things.
Personal belongings.
Okay, I didn't know that effects are called personally.
Thanks.
Okay, fine, cool.
Yeah, so I'm gonna move closer.
There we go.
Alright.
You move closer.
Pip and Sister Mela are, like, quite relieved, and they're like, well, what did you find?
What is there?
Um.
I don't know, let's all open up and see what we have.
Alright, so, da-da-dum.
Alright, the site is littered with arrows, torn scraps of fabric, and odds and ends discarded from Gundren's bags.
If you're, uh, blah blah blah, any, you, as you approach the scene, you identify the horses as belonging to Gundren Rockseeker and Sildar Hallwinter.
Okay.
Okay, that's a test.
The hearse's saddlebags have been looted.
An empty leather map case lies nearby.
They're being looted.
Does it have a map?
Right.
No.
Just in case.
Yes, it's an empty case.
Um.
So, uh, yes.
It looks like our boss has vanished.
Something happened with them.
Up.
Um.
I'm sorry, is yes.
So, well, it's not that someone, yes, your boss, the boss has vanished, and so you're kind of like, well, you've got a couple of choices.
One is you could try to see where the.
Yeah, wait.
Uh, yes, um, wait a second.
Yeah, I'm gonna do do the what is that?
The investigation roll?
Yeah, just roll investigation.
Let me just refresh this.
Alright, so, um, you roll investigation?
Is that what I heard?
Yes.
Yes, yes.
Uh, I did not roll it yet.
Hold on, I think I lost.
Okay, yes.
The seven.
Alright, so what do you, uh, you rolled a seven.
Unfortunately, you find nothing.
Okay.
Oh, no, you rolled a seven, yes.
That is a very bad roll.
You find nothing.
However, as you're all looking around, Pip notices a trail heading north.
Mhm.
Um.
He goes, uh, do you want to go look at what's in there?
At the trail?
And yeah, I know.
Yeah, yeah, I'm gonna go look at the trail.
Alright, you're gonna go look at the That's it, that's all.
Alright.
Okay, so that's where the trail is supposed to be.
I don't know.
Behind these tickets is this trail, right?
MMHM.
And so, um, he, he, you roll a survival check.
Just wait, I'll check.
Okay.
Alright, Zenwan.
Um, goodness, it is good that you rolled well.
Um, what you discover is that about a dozen goblins have come and gone along the trail.
You also see signs of two human-sized bodies being hauled from the ambush site.
Alright.
And what, uh, two, two human bodies?
Two human bodies, yeah, two large bodies, yeah, two human bodies.
Human bodies, they're just lying there.
No, no, they've been dragged.
Oh, okay.
Uh, so let me just make sure you, like, like, uh, trail.
Got it, okay.
Goblin trail.
Signs of two humans dragged.
Got it, okay.
Okay.
Okay, so you can read that.
Alright, so yeah, so there's these two, these, all.
Yes, yes, yeah.
Alright, so, um, you have some choices.
You can continue to Phandalin, or you can go check out what happened.
Whatever you do, you probably want to take a
Short rest.
Or maybe even a long rest.
Oh, okay.
Um, alright, guys, let's.
Let's camp here for tonight and then, uh, decide which way to go, or should I decide and then camp at this place?
Um, no.
Or we can go to Phandalin and then come back.
It's up to you, like, it's totally, like, it's up, the decision is yours.
No, I would.
I don't think there's any point going to Phandalin.
With the boss, with my boss in danger.
Um, so?
Alright, so you want to you want to head north into the into the yeah to wherever the goblins were coming from?
Yes, yes.
Alrighty.
So, I would want to roll and then take a rest.
Alright, so you'll um We're happy about that.
Alright, are you gonna leave the goblins dead where they are, or are you gonna try to move them off the side?
Problems.
I'm gonna leave the webinar.
I'm gonna move the horses to the side and then feed them.
Alright.
Okay, so you head out.
Um, off into the woods, right?
So show you where you're heading off.
Or actually, not into the woods, into the hills.
Perfect.
Okay.
I'm hom.
You're heading off into the hills.
And, uh.
Okay.
Can I make a choice?
Like, can I ask a question about what is the distance to find them?
Like, how long is it gonna take from here?
Um, well, you know, um.
You know, it probably would take you till evening to get there.
Then I would want to drop off these things first, then come back.
No, I mean, that's a totally REA.
Uh, it's a tough choice.
It's a totally reasonable thing.
I mean, like, it's a total, the choice is yours.
Yeah, yeah.
Okay, I want to okay too, can.
If I can make a change, I want to go back to Phandalin.
Do my job.
Oh, you can't.
Okay, and then come back and see what the hell's going on.
Yeah, yeah.
Alrighty.
So we are in front of them.
You are in Phandalin.
The rutted track emerges from a wooden hillside, and you catch your first glimpse of Phandalin.
The town consists of 40 or 50 simple log buildings, some built on old fieldstone foundations, more old ruins, crumbling stone walls covered in ivory and briars.
Surround the newer houses and shops, showing how this must have been a much larger town in centuries past.
Most of the newer buildings are set on the sides of the cart rack, which widens into a muddy main street as it climbs toward a ruined manor house on a hillside at the east.
As you approach, you see children playing on the town green and townsfolk tending to chores or running errands at the shops in town.
Many people look at you and smile as you approach, but all return through the businesses.
As you go.
Alright, so, uh, he kind of, like, so I'm told that I should put some signs, some things here so that you know what's going on.
Alright, so, before you left, uh, Gundren kind of gave you some information about the town, right?
Um, he said, so you know where the townmaster's hall is, you know that there's a tavern, a place where you can get rest, called the Stonehill Inn.
There's a smithy, and Barthen's Provisions, just to remind you, is where you're supposed to go to return the provisions.
So I'm gonna tell me a little bit more about this.
You're gonna go to the, you're gonna go here to Barthen's?
And pathways.
Yeah, deliver the provisions and then rest.
Alright, okay.
Okay, so, uh, just so you know, um, because this is not obvious to you, alright, so this is, let me just put some notes here.
This is, uh, place to, place for rest.
A tavern.
Hotel.
Oh man, I really love how Indians call tavern.
Hotel means something different for Indians than it does for Americans.
Yeah.
Hotel is also a place to eat for us.
That's good.
Okay.
Yeah, I know, it confused the living shit out of me when I was in India, like, 20 years ago.
I was like, what the?
Also, tavern means like a place to drink as well.
Yeah, I know.
Um, and so, okay, so, um.
Important detail about the world.
Tavern.
Tavern in this context means place where people go to socialize.
MMHM.
It is not a bar.
Okay.
Right?
It's like the one place everybody goes to to hang out.
Okay, makes sense.
Right?
So, don't think of it as a tavern in the modern sense, where people, like, spend all their time at home, or go to parties, or whatnot.
Amhom.
Think of it as, this is the one place you go to hang out with other people.
Okay, okay.
And it wasn't, you know.
It was more of a social thing than a drinking thing.
Does that make sense?
It's for sale.
Right, and so, uh, Lionshield Coster, that's where you can buy some goods.
The townmaster's obviously where the townmaster lives.
Smithy, you can.
Yes.
Figure it out by just, you know what a smithy is, right?
A smith?
Blacksmith?
Yes, yes.
Sells weapons and other things.
Oh, I see, okay.
What is uh Lionshield Coster, you said?
Goods for sale.
Needs to say it, okay.
It's, uh, it's a, uh, yeah, this, yeah, so this is kind of, like, uh, just, yes, goods for sales.
What kind of goods?
You'd have to go find out.
Okay, sounds good.
Alright, um, okay.
So, where do you want to go?
So, right there, Barthen's Provisions, that's where we said we're going.
Amham.
Uh, Barthen's Provision is the biggest trading post in Phandalin.
It stocks most ordinary goods and supplies, including backpacks, bedrolls, rope, and rations.
The place is open.
Once you arrive, he doesn't, you look around, but he doesn't stock any weapons.
So, as you walk in, the proprietor, Elmina Barthen, a young woman with kindly manner, shows up with her two clerks, Ander and Thistle.
Um she says, Well, who are you?
Um, my name is Zenwan.
And, uh, I'm here to deliver your provisions by Gundren.
Um she goes, Oh, um, do you get, do you give her the contract?
Yes, I give her the contract and uh show, point her to the wagon.
Uh, so Elmina sends her two men, and she goes, Oh, well, yes, yes, yes.
Well, here you are, and she gives you, uh, 19 gold pieces.
Okay.
Right, so she, you know, she pays you.
She goes, but wasn't Gundren supposed to be here?
Well, he said he's gonna arrive a little later, but he sent me to deliver the provisions first.
So you don't tell her that you think he might be captured.
Yeah, okay.
Okay, that's cool.
Not yet.
I don't know who I can trust here.
Okay, um.
She goes, well, I'm.
We never know, like, she could have planned the same, you know, she could have.
Yeah, so she goes, I really am worried, he's a good friend of mine.
Oh, I see, okay.
I don't know, I wanted to do an inside troll.
Alright, roll an insight roll.
Uh, well.
Sorry.
No, okay, that's a bad rule.
Alright, but yes, but there are other people in your party who can also roll insight.
Um, roll 3 or D20S, and I'll tell you, okay, uh, Sister Garaele has got a reel, has a plus 4, so have her roll insight.
Okay, okay, how can I do that?
Just roll a D20 and add 4 backslash.
So, here.
You type our D20 plus 4 backslash.
Okay.
Slash R slash D set.
Slash R.
Okay, okay.
Okay, D plus, okay, so that's a 14 backslash.
Okay.
Alright.
Um, Sister Garaele kind of turns to you and says.
She looks legit to me.
Okay.
So, yeah, then.
And then pauses, and then pauses and says, and while you're thinking about what to do, she turns around and says.
Okay.
Is Gundren a good friend of yours?
And Elmina says, well, yes, yes, yes.
Yes, he is.
He's a very good friend of mine, and I'm very worried that he didn't show up.
He was very excited.
Okay.
Excited for what?
Sister Garaele questions.
Yeah, well, she, uh, well, uh, he was very excited by his talk of discovering the lost mind of the Phandelver Pact in the nearby, here, detail, here, hills.
Okay, roll a DC-10 intelligence history check.
Just doing our uh thing.
Yeah, everybody roll a history check.
D10?
Yeah, just roll a history check and you have to beat the number 10 backslash.
Oh, I see, okay.
Uh, where's the history?
Okay, got it.
Yes, yes, yes.
Alright, what did you roll?
Ah, there.
2.
Alright, how about okay, what roll?
Let's roll some more D20S for role A D20 for a let's see who's got 5.
Uh, Viera has a plus 5, so roll for her.
I'll be talking.
Yep.
What did she get?
17?
Well, Viera goes, oh, well, that's interesting.
Right, let me just show you this.
Okay, this is uh, this is their sort of artwork of you.
Oh, nice.
Okay, this is the attack of the goblins.
Of the, um, the attack by the goblin.
She goes, Well, Phandelver, the Phandelver Pact?
Well, I know a lot about that.
More than 500 years ago, clans of dwarves and gnomes made an agreement known as the Phandelver Pact.
By which they would share a rich mine in a wondrous cavern known as the Wave Echo Cave.
In addition to its mineral wealth, the mine contained great magical power.
Human spellcasters allied themselves with dwarves and gnomes to channel and bind that energy into a great forge called the Forge of Spells, where magic items could be crafted.
Times were good, and the nearby town of Phandalin prospered as well, but disaster struck when bandits swept through the north and laid waste to all in their path.
A powerful bandit force reinforced by evil mercenary wizards attacked Wave Echo Cave to seize its riches and magic treasures.
Human wizards fought alongside their dwarf and gnome allies to defend the Forge of Spells, and the ensuing spell battle destroyed much of the cavern.
Yes.
Few survived the cavern backslash.
The cavens and tremors and knowledge of the location of the Wave Echo Cave was lost.
She pauses.
For centuries, rumors of buried riches have attracted treasure seekers and opportunists to the area around Phandalin, but no one has located the lost mine.
Hmm.
Um, says.
Uh, what is she doing?
Barthen says.
Well.
Ah.
There were, well, that's really interesting, because, uh, Gundren was really convinced he had found it.
Um, okay.
And at this point in time, Sister Garaele goes, Well, if you're not gonna tell her, I am.
And says.
We found him.
Well, we found his horses.
And we found a map case.
And we found two bodies that were dragged away.
She likes goes.
Like, you know, like, you know.
You know.
Is he dead?
Uh, Sister Garaele.
Uh, what?
We don't know.
No, I'd say we don't know.
So you don't know, well, Sister Garaele goes.
Sister Garaele is, you know, very much, you know.
Yeah.
What we do know is that they were alive at the time they were dragged away.
That's comforting.
Elmina goes, what, what, what, you, you, you, you must go save him.
Yes, yes.
So, yeah, we wanted to give you your provisions and then, uh, you know.
What are you doing here?
Go, go, go, go, backslash.
Yeah, we're gonna get some weapons and then go.
Alright, it's , man.
I don't know, I don't know whether it.
There's.
Yeah, yeah, I thought I had three more minutes, right?
So I thought I can.
I was waiting for you to, like, uh, you know, take us to the Stonehill Inn or maybe, you know.
Yes.
But I stepped the Stonehill Inn.
You what?
Alright, we could go to the Stonehill, and I just.
I wanted to be.
Yeah, I'm gonna.
Okay, you want to go to the Stonehill.
Yeah, so I'm gonna tell Barthen that I'm gonna rest here and what is the span of it for tonight and then start in the morning.
Alright.
To find uh Gundren.
In the center of town, opposite the town green, stands a large, newly built roadhouse of fieldstone and rough-hewn timbers.
The common room is filled with local nursing mugs of ale or cider.
With the locals, nursing mugs of ale or cider, all of them eyeing you with curiosity.
Amham.
Okay, let's change.
The ins prepared terror is, uh, the ins prepared terror goes, welcome backslash.
Welcome to Stonehill Inn backslash.
Uh, grab a table backslash.
Enjoy us some beer backslash.
Hm, okay, yes.
And inside, let's relax for tonight.
Right, and while you're there, you see, uh, there's a couple of people there.
There's, uh, two humans and a gnome.
They all kind of look at you and then go back to whatever they were doing.
So, um, go question them.
Ask them any questions.
Or we can stop here.
Alright.
We'll stop here.
Yeah, yeah, we'll stop here and then I'm gonna go later.
Question.
Alright, cool, sounds good.
That's great.
And and uh, what this chat is gonna persist, right?
Uh, in the Roll20?
Alright, sir.
Uh, don't worry, I take.
I recorded the call, I make lots of notes, don't worry.
Okay, okay.
Like, I have a.
You remember all that shit I've been doing for the last several months with Dungeons and Dragons, and you're about, yeah, yeah, yeah, you're gonna see a, you're gonna see the output of it in.
Yes, yes, the mind palace thing.
Right.
But is this gonna stay for my preference?
Which one?
The notes in the chat?
No.
So what you want to do is you want to put those notes in your play.
Okay, let me just tell you how we do this, how I do this.
Hold on.
Good.
Just do this.
No, I think the chat log stays until I press click.
Clear current chat log.
No, it's a very shitty system.
Here's what we'll do.
Okay, you're sending it in this one.
No, no, I'm gonna tell you what we're okay.
There's a Google sheet.
Your notes there.
Okay, okay, I will put my notes there.
Okay.
That's, that's what I do.
Sun Street.
Okay.
So.
So yeah, items, quests, and notes.
So, for example, quests here would be fine.
Say if, uh, follow.
Where is, uh, where, where, follow trail, follow goblin trail.
Amhom.
Okay.
And it was stimulated, that's just.
And then under notes, you might put the thing, uh, items, you say one black rock.
Okay, yep.
You see, item, typically we do it this way, item, quantity.
Amhom.
We all That's all.
So are you also capturing the tie ropes?
Which one?
The die rolls, the die roll mistruths.
Uh, no, not really.
I don't, I don't, Captain.
Okay.
Why?
No, I mean, I thought it would be nice to see just keeping a paper trail, that's it.
Of the game.
Um No, it's okay.
I mean, I just, it's, I don't even know what how we can use it, but I just wanted to keep a log of the Um, okay.
Well, I think I could, I can.
No, if you're not doing, that's fine.
I'll try to keep a lot of that.
No, I don't usually keep a log of the die rolls.
Okay, I think good.
Unless it's something crazy that happens.
Okay, yeah, yeah, cool.
Alright, guys, it was great playing with you, man.
Take care.
Yes, of course it is.
Looking forward for the next quest.